the eye is an organ which gives you
Vision thanks to its photoreceptors
which detect light
the eyes sit in the Bony orbits which
deflect impacts and protect them the
eyes have anatomical layers including
the fibrous vascular and inner layers
and each of these layers has specialized
structure and function
the cornea and sclera comprise the dense
fibrous layer of the eyes they're
continuous with each other and give the
eyeball shape and structure
the sclera provides an attachment site
for your extraocular muscles the
extraocular muscles are found at the
sides of the eyeball and Implement all
of your eye movements when light passes
through the cornea its round shape bends
the light's path focusing it inside the
eye
under the fibrous layer is the eye's
vascular layer which has three
components the ciliary body choroid and
Iris
the choroid is a layer of blood vessels
which Supply the retina which is found
beneath the choroid the iris controls
the pupil which acts like an aperture
shrinking and growing the pupils via
smooth muscle fibers
the ciliary body has two parts muscles
and processes the muscle attaches to the
lens by the processes
the ciliary body also makes aqueous
humor and it is attached to the lens and
can change its shape resulting in a
change in focal length
when Light reaches the inner layer it is
detected to give you sight
the retinas are your eyeballs sensors
and photoreceptors are found within it
each retina is composed of two layers
the neural layer is thicker and is used
for detecting photons while the thinner
pigmented layer maintains the retina and
absorbs stray light that might interfere
with the image captured by the neural
layer in the front the eye's inner layer
is called non-visual since only the
pigmented layer is present while in the
back the eyes inner layer is termed the
retina's optic part since it is here
that one has both retinal layers
at The Retina Center is the macula and
at its Center is the fovea centralis the
fovea has high photoreceptor density
providing the sharpest visual acuity
near the fovea you have your blind spot
here there are no photoreceptors since
this is where the optic disk sends
signals backwards via the optic nerve
behind the lens we find transparent gel
called the vitreous body which fills
space in the posterior chamber
a canal runs from the optic disc to the
lens through this gel it is a fetal
Remnant called the hyaloid canal
remember that while the vitreous body is
in the posterior chamber the aqueous
humor is in the anterior chamber
the lenses between the vitreous body and
the pupil